<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jude Teves</title>
    <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jude Teves</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Jude Michael Teves</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Power Demand Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/capstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/capstone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is our thesis for the Master of Science in Data Science program. Due to its confidentiality, no additional details will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crowd Evacuation Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/crowd-evacuation-dynamics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/crowd-evacuation-dynamics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Authors: Tristan Alba, Prince Javier, and Jude Teves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created a cellular automata model that simulates how people evacuate in the case of a fire emergency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./evac_mrt.gif&#34; alt=&#34;MRT gif&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./evac_msds_20.gif&#34; alt=&#34;MSDS Caseroom gif&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;./evac_intersection_40.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Intersection gif&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Analysis of the Philippine Stock Market</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/ph-stocks-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/ph-stocks-network/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Authors: Tristan Alba and Jude Teves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the movement of stock prices is considered to follow a random walk, each fluctuation does not occur independently but are highly intertwined with the industry and sector a stock belongs to. This relationship of stocks with each other can be effectively mapped using correlation-based networks. In particular, these are networks formed by calculating the correlation between each pair of time series of stock prices with which their links are given by the threshold level of correlation determined from the onset. Not only does this graph capture the complex nature of nancial markets, but is also helpful in revealing internal structure and hidden information in the market. More importantly so, with the fear from the recent financial crisis and bubbles across Asian and Western economies, there is more need to carefully monitor co-movement of stocks and overall dynamics of the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This network approach in studying nancial markets has been implemented by Tse, et al., Dimitrios, et al., and Wen, e al. where they studied stock relationships primarily using correlations. Typically, the resulting networks are huge and requires filtering to reduce complexity of analysis. It is well observed in these literature how stocks network follow a scale-free distribution where a few stocks have heavy influence over many. From exactly this knowledge, programs in asset allocation and risk management involving high degree stocks are derived. Furthermore, correlation analysis can be used in portfolio optimization across domestic and international equities and in effective execution of pairs trading strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this work, we study the relationship between stocks in the Philippine Stock Exchange (PSE) market from 2006 to present. In detail, we look at the temporal evolution of the stocks network attributes, noting stability and changes in the network over time. We also attempt to characterize the topology across various events in history. Lastly, we demonstrate the feasibility of creating a portfolio strategy through the network approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this study, we analyzed the Philippine Stock Market from a network science perspective. We observed how topological parameters vary greatly with time. Furthermore, a degree-based index can serve as viable basis for a portfolio that matches the overall performance of the market. The very high correlation with existing indices such as the PSE All Shares and PSE Index further supports this claim. With limited resources, investors must allocate their funds wisely to stocks that would allow them to outpace or ride the growth of the market. Through correlation-based networks, trading strategies and portfolios can be built to arm investors to take advantage of the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subreddit Recommender System</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/subreddit-recommender/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/subreddit-recommender/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Authors: Titus Jungao and Jude Teves&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civilization Simulation</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/civ-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/civ-simulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Created a cellular automata model that simulates how different human races propagate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![Civ gif](./Civ-world-2.gif) --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PaNet</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/panet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/panet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Authors: Adrian Galido, Shehab Ibrahim, Titus Jungao, and Jude Teves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deep-Learning based Skin Cancer Detection&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>X-Ray Machine Vision</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/xray-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/xray-web/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Authors: Titus Jungao and Jude Teves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web application for detecting cancer given x-ray images&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Inequality Visualization</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/global-inequality-viz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/global-inequality-viz/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Music using AI</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/music-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/music-ai/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of People’s Interests Using Emoji</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/tweet-emoji/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/tweet-emoji/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Authors: Aian Rosales and Jude Teves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People’s interests in a certain area, Makati to be specific, are identified using the people’s tweets with certain emojis. Using Latent Dirichlet Allocation as a clustering technique, tweets with certain emojis can be grouped into 4 major clusters: Food Porn, Current Events, Happy Travels, and K-Pop. The results seem to reflect the overall set of topics that even non-emoji users could have been discussing as well. Themes can be used for guiding businesses in setting up new brand campaigns or releasing new products. Moreover, understanding emojis can further advance machine’s ability to learn context in chat-based conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./wordcloud_groups.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donors Choose Recommendation System</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/donors-choose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/donors-choose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Authors: Tristan Alba, Prince Javier, and Jude Teves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have created a recommender system and a &lt;a href=&#34;http://cyntwikip-choosedonors.herokuapp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;web application&lt;/a&gt; for it as our entry for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kaggle.com/donorschoose/io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Donors Choose Kaggle competition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sea Level Prediction</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/tidal-range/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/tidal-range/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Authors: Trissa Carvajal-Amanse, Joshua Hiwatig, Aian Rosales, and Jude Teves&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Predicted the tidal range for the 4 major ports in the Philippines using 70 years worth of historical data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RECHORD</title>
      <link>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/rechord/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cyntwikip.github.io/project/rechord/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Implemented a system which can detect notes, basic chords, and complex chords with 100% accuracy in real-time if they are played one at a time. However, if a song is played continuously in real-time, the accuracy is 91% for any music which has a tempo of 2 seconds. Slower tempo equates to higher accuracy and vice-versa. This is due to the temporal resolution of the system. The scope of this research is that it is specific to a guitar, though it can be extended to all stringed instruments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
